"sekkaku hareta kara" tte iiwake o hitotsu houri nage
"The sun's finally out", I shout out an excuse
gareeji kara ikioi makase tobidashita
and fly out of the garage eagerly
mokutekichi wa minami e
I head south, pedaling hard toward the ocean
fumikonde iku pedaru wa umi no hou
chizu nante minai kimerareta you na ruuto wa iya
I don't want to take a route that
I already know without looking at a map
dareka no wadachi wa ashi ga torarete komaru
Following someone else's well-worn path
will only slow me down
isshinfuran ni egaku icchokusen rain wa
The straight line drawn with my heart and soul
boku ni shika mirenai panorama e tsuzuku
continues on toward a panorama that only I can see
konma ni-byou no mirai e ima o kirihiraite ike!
Unlock the present into a 0.2 second future!
tonikaku koge
Pedal until the end
Jiraiya Ninja Scrolls:
The Tale of Naruto the Hero-
Pursuers
クソッ 見失ったか。
Damn it, we lost them.
チッ どこへ隠れやがった!?
Where are they hiding?
(デイダラ)フフフッ ポストスーパーフラットは
オイラの芸術だ。 うん。
Post Superflat is
my style of art, hmm!
(デイダラ)喝！
(ゼツ)また派手にやっちゃったよね。
There he goes again,
making a big spectacle.
デイダラに任せたら
こうなることは わかっていた。
We knew things would
end up like this.
This is what happens when
you leave things to Deidara!
でも あれは まずいよね～。
But that's not good, is it?
(デイダラ)
よう！ 見たか？ オイラの芸術。
Hey, did you witness my art?
砂隠れの小バエどもを
一気に始末してやったぜ。 うん。
I got rid of those little gnats
from the Sand in one swoop, hmm!
あっ ああ。
(飛段)何やってんだよ！
Y-Yeah...
What the hell are you doing?!
せっかくの獲物を
あんなボロボロに しちまったら→
If you mess up our precious targets
like that, they'll be useless!
使いもんになんねえじゃねえか！
そんなこと知るか！
オイラの芸術は 爆発で完結すんだ。
Like I care!
My art culminates in an explosion!
(飛段)ざけんじゃねえぞ！ テメエ。
Quit messing around, damn it!
(角都)
なんとか使えそうなのがあった。
I found one we might
be able to use.
(デイダラ)ほらな。
See!
文句 言ってる暇があったら
相棒みたいに働けってんだ。
Instead of complaining,
start working like a real partner!
テメエ 許せねえ！
You're gonna get it!
(角都)行くぞ 飛段！
あっ!?
Let's go, Hidan!
まっ お腹立ちとは思いますが→
I know it's upsetting,
but our comrade calls.
相方さんも呼んでることだし
出発しましょ。
Let's depart.
あ～ クソッ！
Damn it!
(ナルト)うっ…。
(シカマル)ナルト！ コイツらは
火影様の手の者じゃねえ。
Naruto...
These guys aren't under the Hokage!
根の者とかいう 裏の組織らしい。
They're from the underground
organization, the Foundation!
裏だか表だか知んねえが→
I don't care if they're underground
or aboveground!
俺の命をとるなら正々堂々→
If they're trying to kill me,
they should come at me fair and
square with their faces showing!
その面さらして
ぶんどってみろってばよ！
Just try and get me!
ぬあ～！
(アンコ)フフッ 血の気の多い子だこと。
Such a hot-blooded child...
ひゃ～！
影分身の術！
Shadow Clone Jutsu!
コイツら 同じ木ノ葉なのに
どうなってんだ？
We're from the same village,
but these guys...
What's going on?
《シカマル : 火影様の息子である
ナルトを狙うにしても→
Even if they're after
the Hokage's son...
なんで このタイミングなんだ？》
Why now?
そういうことか！
俺たちに構ってくるのはよ→
I get it...
There's another reason
why they've come after us.
別んとこに
目的があるからなんだろ？
ずばり ホントの狙いは→
Bluntly, they want to make sure
Sasuke reaches Orochimaru.
サスケを大蛇丸のもとに
送り届けること。
サスケを？
Sasuke?
(ネジ)大蛇丸のもとへ？
To Orochimaru?
(テンテン)そっか。 だからサスケ君を
連れ戻そうとする私たちが→
I see...
We're trying to bring Sasuke back,
so they're interfering with us!
邪魔なんだ。
(リー)そういうことだったのですか。
So that's how it is.
冗談じゃねえ。
You've got to be kidding!
Well, let 'em try and stop us!
だったら やってみろよ。
返り討ちにしてやっからよ！
I'll kick their butts!
うわっ！
(シカマル)ネジ！ リー！ テンテン！ 走れ！
Neji! Lee! Tenten! Run!
What?!
逃げるってのかよ？
We're gonna run away?!
追うんだよ サスケを！
We're going after Sasuke!
タイマンぶってる場合じゃねえだろ。
We can't be engaging in
one-on-one battles.
それこそ ヤツらの思うツボだ。
And that's exactly what they want...
サスケが どんどん
離れていくだけだろうが。
So Sasuke can get further
and further away.
そうだった。
You're right.
時間食っちまったな ネジ。
We wasted time.
Neji! Can you pinpoint
Sasuke's position?!
サスケの位置 わかるか？
白眼！
Byakugan!
こっちだ！ まだ追いつける。
This way! We can still
catch up to him!
さて アレもなんとかしねえとな。
Now then...
We've got to do something
about that too...
来るぞ！
Here they come!
クソッ 今のでだいぶ
間をつめられちまったぜ。
Damn it... That just cost us
quite a bit of time!
(リー)はぁ～！
ゲジマユ！
ここは リーに任せて→
Bushy Brows!
Let Lee handle this.
We have to keep after Sasuke!
俺たちはサスケを追うんだよ！
おい 何言ってんだ。
What're you saying?!
みんなでサスケを連れて帰るんだ！
We're all going to
bring Sasuke back!
リー すまねえが…。
Sorry, Lee, but...
わかっています！
I understand!
僕がこの人たちを
引きつけておきます！
I'll draw these guys in!
皆さんは先へ！
サスケ君を追ってください！
All of you, go!
Go after Sasuke!
行くぞ！
Let's go!
サスケ君を助けるため
ここは絶対に通しません！
We're going to save Sasuke...
and I'm not letting
a single one of you pass!
シカマル 足止めにリーを使ったのね。
Shikamaru...
You used Lee to hold them back.
あぁ 優先順位を考えたら
少しでもサスケに近づかねえとな。
Yeah...
Considering what takes precedence,
we need to get as close to Sasuke
as possible.
らしいわね。
Looks that way...
逃がしません！
You're not getting away from me!
あっ… うわぁ！
拳を交えてみてよくわかりました。
あなたは強い！
After exchanging blows,
I realize that you are very strong.
その強さに僕は憧れる。
And I admire your strength.
だから あなたと戦えることに→
And so... this opportunity to
fight you fills me with happiness.
無上の喜びを感じてもいます。
ゴホッ ゴホッ… それほどのものでも
ありませんがね。
I'm not as strong as you say,
全力は出しますよ。
but I'll give it
everything I've got.
GUTS
僕だって この戦いに
すべてをかけますから！
I will also give it my all!
はぁ～!!
うっ… うおっ！
第五杜門！ 開！
The Fifth Gate of Closing... open!
(角都)依頼されてたもんだ。
Here's what you requested.
They seem quite damaged.
えっ ずいぶん傷んでる
みたいですが…。
ん？ いらないんなら持ってくぞ。
Yeah... If you're not interested,
I'll take 'em with me.
も… もちろん お預かりします。
利用できるかどうかは→
Of course, I'll take them.
They'll decide whether
they're usable or not...
あの方たちの
判断で決まりますけど…。
文句があるなら言っとけ。
それでもマシなほうだってな。
If they complain, you tell 'em...
These are the better ones.
ふん！
行くぞ。
Let's go.
あぁ ちょっと！
Hey!
Hey, c'mon!
おいおい…。
ハァハァ ハァ ハァ…。
あぁ ったく
どいつもこいつもよ！
Damn it... They're all so...
It doesn't seem like
暁の戦力強化のほう→
あんまり成果が
あがってないらしいな。
there's been much improvement to
the Akatsuki's military power.
急がなきゃならねえってのに。
And here we are in a rush.
他の遺体は バラバラで使いものに
なりそうになかった。
The other corpses were too damaged
to be of any use.
せっかく苦労して
砂隠れから使えそうな人材を→
After all the trouble we went through
to lure talented Hidden Sand
that had potential!
誘い出したってのによ。
That's true. The talented ones
should be handled with care.
そうだよね
人材は大切に扱わないと。
そのとおり！ この野郎が
吹き飛ばしやがるから→
Exactly!
But this idiot set off an explosion
and blew up all the bodies!
みんなバラバラだ！
Shut up!
うるせぇな！ オイラの爆発は
そんじょそこらの爆発じゃねえ！
My explosion isn't just
an average explosion!
芸術なんだよ！
It's art!
Art, my foot!
なにが芸術だよ。
Fine! Go ahead and criticize me!
んだと!? オイラのやり方に
ケチつけるってのか!?
やめとけ！
Enough!
まあ やっちまったもんは
しようがねえ。
What's done is done...
それに 他にも
利用する心当たりが→
Besides...
It's not as though
we don't have other options.
ないわけじゃねえしな。
フンッ。
なんで デイダラをひいきすんだよ！
Why are you taking Deidara's side?!
ヒザシ事件のことを思い出せ。
Remember the Hizashi incident?
デイダラのおかげで 今の暁が
あるようなもんだからな。
It can be said that the Akatsuki exists
thanks to Deidara.
((長門 : 木ノ葉隠れの里の
下人たちと組む気なのか？
Are you thinking of joining up with
the genin from Hidden Leaf Village?
(弥彦)ああ 里は違えど→
Yeah...
Although we're from different villages,
同志といっても
いいかもなって思っている。
I feel like we can
call them comrades.
いつか アイツらと組む日も
来るかもしれないな。
Perhaps the day will come
when we'll team up with them.
ん？
長門 何だそれ？
あの子供たちの？
Nagato, what's that?
Doesn't it belong to those children?
I found it on the road to the village.
村の道で拾ったんだ。
みんなが 村に帰る どさくさで
落としてしまったらしいな。
Since it was chaotic with everyone
trying to get home,
they probably dropped it.
ハッハッハ アイツら また ぬいぐるみが
ないって大騒ぎしてるだろうな。
They're probably making a fuss
about missing their stuffed toy.
All right, I'll go return it to them.
よし 俺が届けてきてやる。
(小南)弥彦。
すぐ戻る ここで待っててくれ。
Yahiko?
I'll be right back.
Wait here.
Damn it!
チッ 実験だとか言って
呼び出しといて→
We get called up for some experiment,
so we come all the way here...
わざわざ来てやったら
何の役割も振らないなんて。
and there's nothing to do?
ふざけてやがるぜ。
Give me a break!
オイラの芸術は 派手すぎて
今度の実験には ふさわしくない。
My art is too extravagant and won't be
of any use for this experiment?!
だと!? 何言ってやがる。
That's bull!
一度 オイラの芸術を見りゃ
そのすばらしさに虜になるぜ。
Anyone who sees my art will be
captivated by its brilliance!
よし ここはひとつ
思いっきり派手にやってやるか。
Fine! I'll give 'em a grand performance!
弥彦…。
Yahiko...
ハァ ハァ ハァ…。
長門…。
Nagato...
ハァ ハァ ハァ…。
くっ…。
うわぁ！
Nagato! Nagato, hang on!
長門！ 長門 しっかりして！
どうして…
どうして こんなことに…。
Why... Why did this happen?
(小南)誰が こんなことを…。
Who did this... Was it you?!
あなたなの？
あなたたちの仕業なの？
Was this your doing?
いいや。 だが村の中で
こんなものを見つけた。
No...
But we found this in the village.
これは…。
This is...!
It's a special kunai the Hidden Leaf's
Hokage uses for his Flying Raijin Jutsu.
木ノ葉隠れの里の火影が→
飛雷針の術に使う特製のクナイだ。
木ノ葉隠れの火影…。
This Hokage... of the Hidden... Leaf...?
Are you saying the Hokage ordered this?
では 木ノ葉の火影が
やらせたというの？
Yeah, probably.
あぁ おそらくな。
For the Hidden Leaf,
木ノ葉隠れの里にすれば→
今回の事件は あるまじき不祥事。
this was an embarrassing
and disgraceful incident...
すべてをなかったことに
したかったんだろう。
They probably wanted it to look like
this never happened.
うぅ… うわぁ！
I'll never forgive him!
(許さない！))
あの日から長門と小南は→
From that day forward,
Nagato and Konan stopped referring to
themselves as Team Jiraiya.
チーム・ジライヤを
名乗ることもなくなった。
つまり あの日を境にして→
In other words, that was the day
that triggered their desire
for revenge against the Hidden Leaf.
木ノ葉隠れに対する復讐心で
動き出したんだよね。
Yeah... The greatest motivator
for humans is revenge.
あぁ 復讐は人間にとって→
最も強力な動機となりうる。
By the way, what's gonna happen
ところでよう
暁の戦力を強化して→
once the Akatsuki strengthens
its military power?
何 始めようってんだい。
Beats me...
You'd have to ask the guys on top.
さぁな。 直接トップのヤツらに
聞いてみりゃいいだろ。
ぶち殺したい
相手がいるんなら→
If there's anyone they want dead, I'll be
happy to blow them up with my art.
いつでも オイラの芸術で
吹っ飛ばしてやるのにな。
まぁ そう遠くない未来
動き出すだろうよ。
Things will start happening in the
near future.
Let's just wait and see.
その日を期待して
待つとしようぜ。
People of Hidden Leaf Village...
木ノ葉の民よ
お前たちもまた→
You must feel the same pain
that I've experienced.
俺と同じ痛みを
知らなければならない。
同じ痛みを知らなければ→
Unless you know the same pain,
ホントに他人のことを
知ることはできないからだ。
you can never really understand
what others have felt.
Pain upon the great nation!
大国に痛みを…。
ぬお～っ！
ゴホ ゴホ…。
Hidden Leaf Style...
木ノ葉流 三日月の舞！
Crescent Moon Dance!
Sasuke...
《サスケのヤツ…》
He's gonna get it when
I catch up to him.
《追いついたら ぶん殴ってやる。
そんな涼しい顔
させねえってばよ》
He's not gonna look
so cool when I'm done...
I'll punch his eyes shut
and make him cry!
コブ腫らして 泣きっ面にしてやる！
That jerk!
たら～っ！
フッ…。
だってよ サスケ。
You heard him, Sasuke...
Three left...
《あと３人
一気にかかって来られる前に→
I wish we could weaken
their strength all at once
ヤツらの戦力を削りたいが…》
before they come at us...
テンテン。
わかってる 今度は私が。
Tenten...
I know... This time, I'll...
Just draw one of them out.
１人だけ引きつけてくれりゃいい。
Don't overdo it.
無理はするなよ。
行って。
Go.
《緊急で
飛び出して来ちゃったから→
We hurried out...
so these are the only scrolls I have...
今 巻物はこれしかない》
や～っ！
《くっ…》
Oh no... This scroll is—!
《やばい…
こっちの巻物は もう…》
Moonlit Night!
朧月夜。
うお～っ!!
My survival supply scroll
came in handy!
《サバイバル用の巻物が
役に立った！》
Soon...
(サスケ)もうすぐだ。
I'll have power very soon!
もうすぐ力を！
Sasuke...
《サスケ…》
Sasuke!
サスケ。
サスケ!!
sonna kimi o nazeka
I don't know why but someone like me
konna boku wa zutto hitei dekinakute
just couldn't reject someone like you
hashitteiru sono senaka o
So I kept running after you
taiyou mitai ni oikaketa
like you were the sun
te ga todokisou na yume wa kachi ga nainda
A dream that's within reach doesn't have any value
zettai ni muri datte iwareru kurai ga ii
I like it better when I'm told it's unreachable
akirameru nante itsudatte dekiru kara
I can give up any time I want
hikihanasaretemo boku wa ganbarou
so I'll keep trying no matter how much we're pulled apart
hito wa doushite ase nagashite kisoiau no ka?
Why do people sweat and fight so hard?
jibun no sonzai o shoumei shitai
I want to prove that I exist
sonna kimi wa kitto
That someone like you has a fear
konna boku niwa nai kodoku ni obieterunda
of being alone that someone like me doesn't have
sono saki niwa daremo inai
There's no one beyond that point
ushiro ni chikadzuku fuan dake
As anxiety closes in from behind
boku ga iru
I will be there
So you're Orochimaru?
皆様 お変わりございませんか。
What did you do to Sasuke?!
You're still as annoying as ever...
美空ひばりです。
Sasuke, I'm here to take you back!
今日も
皆さんに喜んでいただける歌を→
Give me a break!
What can a loser like you do?
選んだつもりです。
どうぞ 最後まで
ごゆっくり ご覧ください。
I'll take you back by brute force
if necessary...
Next time on
Naruto Shippuden: "Collision"
I'm not going to lose to you!